RYAN DOWLINGSOKA

ryan@dowlingsoka.com · linkedin.com/in/ryandowlingsoka/

Experienced Technical Artist with a demonstrated history of working in the AAA video game industry. Skilled in Unreal Engine 4, Unity, Houdini, C#, C++, Python, and HLSL/GLSL. Strong arts and design professional, focused on engine tooling, rendering techniques, material and shader work, and procedural content.

EXPERIENCE

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

LEAD TECHNICAL ARTIST, MICROSOFT STUDIOS - THE COALITION, VANCOUVER

Lead Technical Artist at the Coalition. Engine, rendering, content, tools, prototyping, project management, UI, Fluid Ninja integration, Unreal Engine 5 integration. Manager and primary content creator of a small team of technical artists working with all disciplines to deliver creative and artistic vision.

SEPTEMBER 2017 – MARCH 2021

SENIOR TECHNICAL ARTIST, MICROSOFT STUDIOS - THE COALITION, VANCOUVER

Senior Technical Artist role for Gears of War. Engine, rendering, content, tools, ui, and visual effects work.

JANUARY 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2017

TECHNICAL ARTIST, MICROSOFT STUDIOS - THE COALITION, VANCOUVER

Technical Artist on Gears of War Ultimate Edition, and Gears of War 4

AUGUST 2012 – DECEMBER 2013

TECHNICAL ARTIST, MICROSOFT STUDIOS - VICTORIA

Technical Artist on Microsoft Holo-lens

GAMES

2020

GEARS 5: HIVEBUSTERS

Senior Technical Artist

2020

GEARS TACTICS

Senior Technical Artist

2019

GEARS 5

Senior Technical Artist

GAMES CONT.

2016

GEARS OF WAR 4

Technical Artist

2015

GEARS OF WAR ULTIMATE EDITION

Technical Artist

2016

GEARS OF WAR 4

Technical Artist

EDUCATION

2012

BFA IN VISUAL EFFECTS, SAVANNAH COLLEGE OF ART AND DESIGN

SKILLS

- Unreal Engine 3, 4, & 5
- Unity
- Houdini
- C++
- Photography
- Game Design
- World Building

- Substance Designer
- Maya
- HLSL/GLSL
- C#
- Graphic Design
- Python
- Material Networks